<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>News on eMoflon Project Site</title>
    <link>https://emoflon.org/</link>
    <description>Recent content in News on eMoflon Project Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://emoflon.org/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>eMoflon::IBeX</title>
      <link>https://emoflon.org/ibex/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://emoflon.org/ibex/</guid>
      <description>Feature Overview eMoflon::IBeX-GT Feature Overview eMoflon::IBeX-TGG Feature Overview Operational Strategies Download Getting Started Development Support eMoflon::IBeX is an open source tool suite to implement incremental model transformations formally based on the notion of graph transformations. Graph transformations are a declarative and rule-based way to define how a graph (our model) changes. Usually, this is done by writing transformation rules that describe preconditions, i.e., patterns that state when a rule should be applied, and postconditions that state how the rule will change our model.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>eMoflon::Neo</title>
      <link>https://emoflon.org/neo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://emoflon.org/neo/</guid>
      <description>eNeo supports model management as a layer over Neo4j, a fairly well-known graph database. eNeo uses eMSL (the eMoflon Specification Language), a uniform modeling language for metamodeling and modeling, specifying patterns, graph constraints, rules, and triple graph grammars, all in the same uniform textual syntax with advanced support for modularity and reuse via refinement. eNeo provides an export of models (with all referenced metamodels) to Neo4j, as well as an export of patterns, constraints, rules, and triple rules to Cypher, the query and transformation language used by Neo4j.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>eMoflon::Neo New tutorials available</title>
      <link>https://emoflon.org/new-neo-tutorials/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://emoflon.org/new-neo-tutorials/</guid>
      <description>There are three new tutorials to get started with eMoflon::Neo. Check out our getting started page.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting started with eMoflon</title>
      <link>https://emoflon.org/getting-started/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://emoflon.org/getting-started/</guid>
      <description> eMoflon::IBeX To get started with eMoflon::IBeX, you can use our tutorial on GitHub together with the pre-built eMoflon::IBeX Eclipse application.
If you encounter any issues with the tutorial, feel free to open an issue on GitHub.
eMoflon::Neo To get started with eMoflon::Neo, you can use our tutorials together with the pre-built eMoflon::Neo Eclipse application. Currently, there are the following tutorials available:
(Meta-)Modeling with eMoflon::Neo Graph Transformation (GT) with eMoflon::Neo Triple Graph Grammars (TGGs) with eMoflon::Neo </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publications</title>
      <link>https://emoflon.org/publications/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://emoflon.org/publications/</guid>
      <description>Over the years, eMoflon has been applied in diverse application scenarios and domains. In the following, we provide a collection of relevant publications. If you are using or have used eMoflon in a project, publication, lecture, or similar, please contact us.
List of Publications 2022 &amp;ldquo;Graph-Based Specification and Automated Construction of ILP Problems&amp;rdquo;.
Sebastian Ehmes, Maximilian Kratz, Andy Schürr. &amp;ldquo;Local Consistency Restoration Methods for Triple Graph Grammars&amp;rdquo;. Lars Fritsche. 2021 &amp;ldquo;eMoflon: : Neo - Consistency and Model Management with Graph Databases&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Download</title>
      <link>https://emoflon.org/download/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://emoflon.org/download/</guid>
      <description>eMoflon::IBeX Pre-built Eclipse Application (IBeX) Pre-built Virtual Machine (IBeX VM) Eclipse Update Site (IBeX) eMoflon::Neo Pre-built Eclipse Application (Neo) Pre-built Virtual Machine (Neo VM) Eclipse Update Site (Neo) eMoflon::IBeX There are three ways to download eMoflon::IBeX:
The pre-built Eclipse application The pre-built virtual machine The Eclipse update site. We recommend the usage of our pre-built Eclipse application.
Pre-built Eclipse Application (IBeX) You can download the latest version of our pre-built Eclipse application from the release section of our GitHub repository.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>eMoflon::Neo Eclipse build and VM released</title>
      <link>https://emoflon.org/neo-eclipse-and-vm/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://emoflon.org/neo-eclipse-and-vm/</guid>
      <description>Now there are two easy ways to get started with eMoflon::Neo: Our new pre-built Eclipse application and the pre-built virtual machine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Webpage</title>
      <link>https://emoflon.org/new-webpage/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://emoflon.org/new-webpage/</guid>
      <description>We launched the new eMoflon webpage today!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://emoflon.org/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://emoflon.org/contact/</guid>
      <description>You can send us an &amp;#32;&amp;#32; . Feel free to open issues on GitHub if you find any issues in eMoflon.
Technische Universität Darmstadt Department of Electrical Engineering and Information Technology Real-Time Systems Lab Merckstr. 25 64283 Darmstadt, Germany</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Development</title>
      <link>https://emoflon.org/dev/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://emoflon.org/dev/</guid>
      <description>eMoflon is developed jointly at the Real-Time Systems Lab, TU Darmstadt (TUDa) and the Database and Information Systems Group, Paderborn University (UPB). You can find the list of contributors on the eMoflon developer page.
The source code of eMoflon is available at our GitHub organization.
eMoflon::IBeX eMoflon::IBeX-specific development workspace set-up steps are available in the README.md file of the eMoflon::IBeX repository. We recommend the usage of our pre-built Eclipse application to start your development workspace.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Development Team</title>
      <link>https://emoflon.org/dev-team/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://emoflon.org/dev-team/</guid>
      <description>eMoflon is developed jointly at the Real-Time Systems Lab, TU Darmstadt (TUDa) and the Database and Information Systems Group, Paderborn University (UPB). Feel free to contact us.
Current Developers Nils Weidmann (UPB, eMoflon::Neo) Lars Fritsche (TUDa, eMoflon::IBeX) Sebastian Ehmes (TUDa, eMoflon::IBeX) Maximilian Kratz (TUDa, eMoflon::IBeX) Adrian Möller and many other student developers. Former Developers Scientists: Erhan Leblebici, Roland Speith (né Kluge), Gergely Varró, Anthony Anjorin. Student developers: Tobias Niehues, Isabella Nunes Grieser, Marek Daniv, Nicolas Stahl (né Acero), Mario Treiber, Jannik Hinz, Patrick Robrecht, Robin Oppermann, Sascha Zander, Anne-Sophie Ettl, Thomas Kovac, Alexander Schleich, Nico Wombacher, Lars Kliegel, Lukas Neumann, and many more.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
